# 哈喽 大家好
Hello everyone
# 最近我伯爷说这个灯笼椒
Recently, uncle said that the dried pimentos
# 他以前买的放的时间够长了
that he bought has been sitting around for long enough.
# 再不吃要坏了
It’s going to go bad if we let it sit for longer.
# 然后为了想这个灯笼椒怎么吃
So in order to use these pimentos,
# 我让我伯爷去买了点四季豆回来
I asked my uncle to get some French beans.
# 然后今天正好跟大家分享一下
I will share it with you.
# 我们家庭小灶做干煸四季豆
How to make tasty dry-fried french beans at home
# 不用宽油炸怎么把它做得
without Kuan You.
# 也能做的很好吃吧
（注：因语意通顺的关系，本句与上两句一起翻译）
# 我先把海椒剪了
I will first cut the dried chilis
# 放了好久了
It’s been sitting around for a long time.
# 硬是再放（久点）要不得了
We’d have to throw it out if it sits for longer.
# 再不吃都发霉了噶
It will get molded.
# 就是
Right.
# 我们一般这个灯笼椒很少用来炒菜
We rarely use pimentos for stir fry.
# 灯笼椒的话它主要是出香味
It is usually used for its aroma.
# 它是不辣的也出不了什么颜色
It’s not spicy and doesn’t add any color to the dish.
# 待会我们再加点这个
We will add some of this later,
# 再加一点我们自己这个小米辣
some "Xiaomila" chili pepper.
# 这个就辣安
This is spicy,
# 这个出辣味的
it gives spiciness.
# 子弹头的话就出颜色
"Zidantou" chili pepper, on the other hand, gives color.
# 这个四季豆炒出来香哦
This will be aromatic.
# 香 油都没得等哈儿你炒来看香不香嘛
Aromatic? You don’t even add oil, let’s see if it will be aromatic.
# 你又不放油
You don’t even put oil.
# 你放心四伯爷
Relax, uncle.
# 我不是说不放油
I’m not saying we are not putting oil at all.
# 是不拿油来炸
We just don’t deep fry.
# 哦喔 那还差不多
Oh, that sounds better.
# 我剪这个 四伯爷你掐四季豆
I will cut this. Could you please break the beans, uncle?
# 这个咋子嘛 撕过嘎
How? Do I just tear it?
# 把老筋撕了就是
Right, just remove the hard fibers.
# 大四季豆的那个筋就多了
Older french beans are more fibrous.
# 老噶
Old.
# 嗯
Right.
# 还是坏的比较多哦 四伯爷
Many of them have gone bad, uncle.
# 坏的就丢了噻 不要噻
We should throw them out then, don’t use them.
# 我都剪了好几个坏的了
Couple of ones I cut were bad.
# 再不吃发霉了
It will go bad if we still don’t use them.
# 好了 这个干辣椒我剪好了
Ok. Now I’ve cut all the chilies.
# 我把这个捞一下
I’m transferring them to another bowel.
# 这个（辣椒）籽太多了
There are too many seeds.
# 我们把这个籽去掉一些
We will remove some seeds.
# 这个干煸四季豆的话就用这个五花肉
Let’s get some pork belly
# 给它切成小颗粒切碎
And mince them.
# 我们做干煸四季豆
When we make dry-fried french beans,
# 放肥一点的这个猪肉的话
add some pork,
# 它出来的猪油可以把味道吸在这个四季豆上面
the beans absorb flavour from rendered fat.
# 所以就会有味道有盐味
It would be more flavourful.
# 这样子整起肯定好吃
It’s tastier.
# 把这个肉宰哈宰哈就可以了
Just chopt the pork.
# 这个肉准备好了
Now, the pork is ready.
# 再切点姜蒜
Let’s chop some garlic and ginger as well.
# 反正在自己家里做的话就随便一点
We can improvise when cooking at home.
# 噶 四伯爷
Right, uncle?
# 姜还是宰哈
We chop the ginger.
# 然后这个再给它配点其它东西
Then we add some other ingredients,
# 放点花椒
some Sichuan peppercorn.
# 哎呀 好多哦放
Wow, so much!
# 这个就是要有麻味才好吃安
It tastes better when it's numbing.
# 然后再配点这个芽菜
Let’s add some "Ya Cai" (Sichuan preserved mustard greens) too.
# 给它配在一起
Put them together.
# 炒出来的话就更有味道
It’s more flavourful.
# 好
Ok.
# 差不多配齐了就可以炒了四伯爷
We’ve done all the prep and are ready to cook, uncle.
# 可以嘛 干嘛
Let’s cook then!
# 干海椒 肉 芽菜 花椒 姜蒜
Dried chili pepper, pork, Ya Cai, Sichuan peppercorn, ginger, garlic.
# 来嘛
Let’s go!
# 干嘛
Go!
# 齐了
Ready!
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First, let’s heat the wok.
# 锅烧热之后加入适量的油滑锅
Add some oil to grease the wok.
# 滑好锅之后将热油倒出
Pour out the oil after greasing the wok.
# 再加入适量的底油烧热
Then add some base oil.
# 油温5成热之后撒入适量的食用盐
When the oil reaches 150°C, add some salt.
# 这一步的目的是让四季豆进油盐
This is to make sure the beans are put in salted oil.
# 然后加入处理好的四季豆转中小火翻炒6分钟
Add the beans, turn the heat to medium-low and stir fry for 6 minutes.
# 这一步必须将四季豆炒熟炒至表面焦香
Cook until the beans are lightly brown.
# 同学们切记不熟的四季豆容易引发食物中毒
Friends, be sure to keep in mind that uncooked beans are toxic.
# 炒熟之后倒出备用
Remove the beans, set aside.
# 然后直接加入剁好的猪肉末炒香爆出猪油
Add minced pork, render the fat, and release the aroma.
# 猪肉爆香之后加入准备好的花椒芽菜姜蒜末爆香
Then add Sichuan peppercorn, Ya Cai, ginger and garlic, fry until fragrant.
# 然后加入剪好的灯笼椒炒香
Add cut pimentos, saute
# 灯笼椒炒香之后加入四季豆翻炒几下
Add beans to combine,
# 翻炒均匀之后开始调味
then start seasoning.
# 加入适量的食用盐撒入锅中
Add some salt.
# 同学们炒四季豆可以适当的多加一些盐这样更加地入味
You can put a little more salt than usual to incorporate more flavour.
# 再撒入一些鸡精 不喜欢的同学可以不放
Add chicken bouillon, you can opt it out if you don’t like it.
# 最后加入少许陈醋从锅边淋入
Sprinkle some vinegar along the side of the wok.
# 翻炒均匀炒出锅气之后即可出锅装盘
Mix it until everything is fully combined, remove the beans from the wok and plate.
# 可以了四伯爷
It’s done, uncle.
# 尝哈看四伯爷
Please have a taste.
# 尝哈看嘛
Try it.
# 我们这一次用了大量的这个灯笼椒
We used lots of pimentos this time.
# 灯笼椒的主要作用就是提香
The purpose is to make the dish more fragrant.
# 然后这个四季豆被我在锅里面用油
And the beans are brown in the wok,
# 先把它爆焦了已经很香了
so it’s already very appetizing.
# 然后再爆之前油里面是放了一点盐的
Then, because we added some salt in the oil
# 所以这个四季豆中间都是有味道的
The saltiness has penetrated the beans.
# 在家里面做的话
To cook it at home,
# 就放点油先把它炒焦炒熟
put some oil, stir fry it until lightly browned and cooked.
# 然后再炒其他的佐料
Add other ingredients,
# 再一起炒
and cook together
# 不用花太多油去做这个菜
This dish doesn’t need to much oil
# 好吃
Tasty!
# 安逸
nice
# 但是干辣椒的这个籽啊太多了
But pimento has too many seeds
# 去掉90%的籽
Remove 90% of the seeds
# 这个壳给它爆香了
Fry to release the aroma of the pimento itself.
# 炒出来很香
It is very fragrant.
# 人家都说这个四季豆油盐不进
It is said that it’s hard for french beans to absorb oil and salt.
# 这回我就让它进了油盐的噻
This time I made it happen.
# 这道四季豆这个做法
I recommend you to try
# 强烈推荐你们去试下
this french bean recipe. (注：此处调换两句话位置更通顺些)
# 好了
Ok.
# 本期视频就到这里
It’s the end of the video.
# 可以这个四季豆炒得
The french beans are really nice.
# 拜拜
Bye!
# 你尝一下这个肉四伯爷
Try the pork.
# 这个肉也好吃
It’s tasty too.
# 肯定噻
Of course!
# 那下次不要宰这么碎 宰大块点好夹点
Next time don’t mince it too small, keep it bigger so it’s easier to be picked up.
# 宰碎点出味道安
You get more flavour out of it when it’s minced small.
# 夹都夹不起来你宰碎很了
But I couldn’t pick it up, it’s too small.
# 这个肉也好吃
（注：从这句开始和上面重复了，视频中只有一次这段对话）
# 肯定噻
# 下次不要宰这么碎
# 宰大块点的好夹
# 要宰碎点出味道安
# 夹都夹不起来你宰碎很了
# v标题（翻译主要意思即可，不要超过 100 个字符）
# 厨师长分享：“干煸四季豆”的真家常做法，不用宽油也能真香，下饭神器！
The Real homely way of “dry-fried French beans”. No need for Kuan You (broad oil)!